# **Eray Aydın**

Web Application Developer, Linux SysAdmin, Speaker

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly-skilled software development professional bringing more than 9 years in software design, development and integration. Web Developer offering advanced knowledge of language PHP, HTML5, CSS3, NodeJS and Python, as well as extensive experience with Linux.

#### **SKILLS**

- Advanced knowledge of PHP
- Advanced knowledge of Python
- Experienced on NodeJS and Socket.io
- API design knowledge
- Knowledge of HTML5 and CSS3
- Database schema designing
- Knowledge and experience on Laravel Framework, Slim Micro-Framework and Symfony Framework / Components.

- Linux SysAdmin (CentOS, Arch Linux, L&X Ubuntu, Debian, Slackware, Mint, Black Arch)
- Shell Scripting
- Built scalable server
- Basic knowledge of C and C++
- Built applications with MySQL and MongoDB
- Django and Flask Frameworks

#### **WORK HISTORY**

# Özgür Yazılım A.Ş., Remote — Web Application Developer

Jun 2019 - Present

- Develop and maintain custom Drupal packages.
- Create and service Drupal RestAPI.
- Strengthened developmental methodologies by introducing a code quality document.
- Wrote minimal Python CLI applications to maintain the PHP Drupal CMS website.
- Python Django and RestAPI

#### **Teleskop**, Remote — Python Developer

Aug 2018 - Dec 2018

Develop and contribute to the Python Flask API application.

#### Odaxa Bilişim Teknolojileri, Remote — Web Application Developer

Feb 2018 - Apr 2018

- Develop and maintain Laravel packages.
- Developed Laravel E-Commerce application.

# **Softnetta,** Konya — Web Application Developer and Linux SysAdmin

Sep 2017 - Dec 2017

- Developed E-Commerce System.
- Debugged and modified many software components.
- Collaborated an old project.
- Upgrade/Shift old Laravel project to new version.
- Integrated with GIT version control system.
- Created an ecosystem for development.

# Coder Offis, Konya — Web Application Developer, Linux SysAdmin and Project Manager

Jun 2016 - Aug 2016

- Collaborated with product management to design, build and test systems.
- Debugged and modified software components.
- Responsible for in-page SEO quality and UI/UX features.
- Developed many of Laravel Framework private packages.
- Developed custom CMS with module based package powered.
- Led the team that developed multiple websites using LAMP, PHP 7 OOP and Laravel Framework.
- Designed Laravel-based multi-threaded admin web applications.
- Developed object-oriented software, including package and version control based company CMS.

#### Webjektif, Konya — Web Application Developer, Linux SysAdmin

Jan 2016 - May 2016

- Designed and developed transactional and analytical data structures.
- Modified existing software to correct errors, adapt to new hardware and improve performance.
- Designed booking and reservation application components.
- Designed and developed custom CMS with module based package powered.
- Installed and managed VestaCP on CentOS webserver with PHP 7 support.
- Many of Laravel Framework private and public packages.
- Responsible for schema designing and planning of databases.
- Worked on B2B Tourism and news portal websites.

# **Temel Bilişim,** Konya — Web Application Developer, Frontend Designer and Linux SysAdmin

Jun 2010 – Jan 2016

- Built, tested and deployed scalable, highly available and modular software products.
- Strengthened developmental methodologies by introducing a code quality document.
- Wrote and implemented scripts to enhance user experience and integrated scripts with the company specific CMS.
- Developed shared central authentication system in PHP for intranet applications.
- Coded 100+ websites using PHP, HTML, CSS and Javascript.
- Designed intranet and finance application components.
- Wrote PHP applications in MVC architecture.
- Installed and managed WHM/Cpanel on CentOS webserver with PHP 5 and PHP 7 support.
- Integrated WHMCS and WHM API with web server.
- Responsible from the high traffic mail server and web server.
- Developer team director and project leader.
- Implemented application server for version control.
- Responsible for IE compatibility and in-page SEO.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### Iskenderun Technical University, Hatay — Computer Engineering

2018 - 2020

Member of Computer Engineering Students Club, Chess Club and Robotic Club.

# **Selcuk University**, Konya — Special Student of Computer Engineering (English Education)

2016 - 2018

Member of Computer Engineering Students Club and Robotic Club. Software Process Improvement webinar, including Ethical Hacking. Special student of 'Izmir Economy University'.

# **Izmir Economy University**, Izmir — Student of Computer Engineering (English Education)

2016 - 2018

Computational Science and Engineering coursework.

## **Mevlana (Rumi) University**, Konya — Student of Computer Engineering (English Education)

2014 - 2016

Member of Robotic Club. Computational Science and Engineering coursework. University has been closed in 2016.

#### **AFFILIATIONS**

#### **Kodluyoruz PHP Bootcamp** — *Trainer*

Prepare a Beginner level PHP Bootcamp for 34 students with 35 hours.

#### **KonyaPHP** — Leader, Speaker

Lead of organization. Creating events and contact with other speakers. Speaking about PHP, Linux and Web Development Technologies. Organization of the event's schedule.

#### **Linux Turkey - Moderator**

Moderator of a community with 5000+ members. Answering questions in the community and helping others. Manage of questions and moderate.

# **AnkaraPHP** - Speaker

Member of organization. Speaking on events about PHP and Laravel Framework.

#### **CERTIFICATIONS**

**Akademik Bilişim 2017**, INETD, Aksaray — *Teacher of 'Modern Web and PHP' Course* Feb 2017

**Akademik Bilişim 2016,** INETD, Ankara — Arduino 1st Level Course

Açık Kaynak Günleri 2015, Tutev, Ankara — Capture The Flag (Hacking) 2nd

**Linux Summer Camp 2015,** LKD, Bolu — Web Programming with Django and Javascript

Aug 2015

GDG DevFest 2014, Google, İzmir — Certificate of Participation

Nov 2014